THE CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS AND EVENTS OF THIS DRAMA ARE FICTIONAL
이 드라마의 등장인물, 조직, 사건은 허구입니다.
Stab him, you bastard!
찔러라, 이 새끼야!
Damned.
저주 받은.
You know what?
그거 알아?
When Yongdae was here on behalf of the boss,
용대가 사장님을 대신해서 여기 왔을 때 ,
The bastard was already waiting here.
그 놈은 이미 여기서 기다리고 있었어.
And apparently, damn it,
그리고 분명히, 젠장,
When you were released from the hospital, he was there too.
당신이 병원에서 퇴원했을 때 그도 거기 있었습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
What is it with you two?
너희 둘은 무슨 사이야?
Chief Seo.
서 실장님.
He has nothing to do with me.
그는 나와 아무 관련이 없습니다.
I really don't know anything. OK?
나는 정말로 아무것도 모른다. 좋아요?
Then it doesn't matter if he dies.
그러면 그 사람이 죽어도 상관없어요.
Fucking asshole.
빌어먹을 새끼.
You Hurensohn!
휴렌손이여!
Asshole!
항문!
Of ...
의 ...
Motherfucker.
개자식아.
You Hurensohn.
당신은 휴렌손입니다.
It was you. You were the traitor.
당신이었습니다. 당신은 배신자였습니다.
You lousy pig!
이 형편없는 돼지야!
Die!
주사위!
At three. One two three!
3시에. 하나 둘 셋!
- You dirty pig! Son of a bitch!
- 더러운 돼지야! 개자식!
-Stand up! -Let go, you bastard!
-일어서세요! - 놔, 이 새끼야!
-Seo Jongryeol, you wanker! -Let go, you pigs!
-서종렬, 이 멍청아! - 놔, 돼지들아!
No! Drop them!
아니요! 버려라!
-Out of the way! -You asshole!
-방법 중! - 이 멍청아!
-Let go of me, damn it! -Stop!
- 놔, 젠장! -멈추다!
-Take him away! -Let me go!
-그를 데려가세요! - 놔줘!
-Kwon Seungho! You asshole! -You bastard!
- 권승호! 이 멍청아! -이 개자식!
Dohyung, are you ok?
도현아, 괜찮아?
Dohyung!
도형!
Dohyung! No!
도형! 아니요!
Call a damn ambulance! Come on!
빌어먹을 구급차를 불러라! 어서 해봐요!
Dohyung.
도형.
Junmo.
준모.
You are a police officer.
당신은 경찰관입니다.
Never forget that.
그 점을 절대 잊지 마세요.
Yes OK. And now we're taking you to a hospital.
응 알았어. 이제 우리는 당신을 병원으로 데려가고 있습니다.
Put him on my back!
그를 내 등에 업어주세요!
Fuck!
못쓰게 만들다!
No!
아니요!
Hey, stay with us! Hold on!
이봐, 우리와 함께있어! 기다리다!
THE WORST OF EVIL
최악의 악
"Sports facilities."
"스포츠 시설."
"Maritimer Tourismuskomplex"
"마리티머 관광산업단지"
"Urbaner Grünpark."
"Urbaner Gr??npark."
"Hightech-Industriebezirk."
"하이테크-인더스트리베지르크".
Choi Jungbae, you shithead.
최정배, 이 멍청아.
"Investitionsaufruf."
"조사우프루프."
"CEO Jung Gicheul."
"정기철 대표님."
So you want to start over as a clean businessman?
그럼 깨끗한 사업가로 다시 시작하고 싶나요 ?
We can't live like this forever.
우리는 영원히 이렇게 살 수 없습니다.
We also have to live like decent people.
우리도 괜찮은 사람처럼 살아야 해요.
I said there's no "we", you lousy bastard.
내가 "우리"는 없다고 말했잖아, 이 형편없는 놈아.
We?
우리?
Are we also included in this plan?
우리도 이 계획에 포함되어 있나요?
Gicheul.
기철.
Do you know our boys' names?
우리 애들 이름 아시나요?
Do you know them all?
당신은 그들을 모두 알고 있나요?
Hey, Kwangryul.
안녕하세요, 광률님.
Your dream is a barbecue restaurant, right?
당신의 꿈은 바비큐 레스토랑이죠?
I'm sorry for that.
나는 그 일에 대해 유감이다.
If I die today, I won't be able to help.
오늘 내가 죽으면, 나는 도울 수 없을 것이다.
Jaehoon.
재훈.
Congratulations on your sister's wedding.
언니의 결혼을 축하드립니다 .
My gift was too simple.
내 선물은 너무 단순했다.
Kyuhyung, you said your father has diabetes.
규형아, 아버지가 당뇨병을 앓고 계시다고 했어 .
I bought medicine for him. Take her with you.
나는 그를 위해 약을 샀습니다. 그녀를 데리고 가세요.
Shoot.
사격.
Shoot!
사격!
That's what Jung Gicheul would do.
그게 정기철이 할 일이다.
Listen, asshole. Clean or dirty,
들어봐, 병신아. 깨끗하든지 더러운지,
Rags remain rags.
넝마는 넝마로 남아 있습니다.
You fucking son of a bitch.
이 빌어먹을 개자식아.
Kill me. I'm going to die anyway, why not by you.
나를 죽여라. 어차피 난 죽을 텐데 왜 당신 곁에는 안 되겠습니까?
Gicheul.
기철.
It's enough.
충분 해.
Everything is over.
모든 게 끝났어.
If it wasn't for me,
내가 아니었다면,
you would never have made it this far.
당신은 여기까지 도달하지 못했을 것입니다.
you couldn't live like that.
당신은 그렇게 살 수 없었습니다.
You didn't achieve this alone.
당신 혼자서 이것을 달성한 것이 아닙니다.
We all risked our lives for this.
이를 위해 우리 모두는 목숨을 걸었습니다.
You smug bastard!
잘난 척하는 놈아!
We are all friends.
우리는 모두 친구입니다.
Let's end it here.
여기서 끝내자.
A nice catch here!
여기서 좋은 캐치!
Guys, I'm here,
얘들아 나 여기 있어
because I have a very incriminating complaint about someone
왜냐면 내가 누군가에 대해 매우 비난적인 불만을 갖고 있기 때문입니다.
for aiding and abetting murder.
살인을 돕고 방조한 죄로.
Who made the ad?
광고는 누가 만들었나요?
Are you here?
여기 계세요?
Well, I see
글쎄요.
You have quite a heated confrontation here.
당신은 여기서 꽤 열띤 대결을 벌이고 있습니다.
So this is how it ends.
그래서 이것이 끝나는 방법입니다.
What a disastrous ending to the novel.
소설의 참으로 비참한 결말입니다.
Gicheul.
기철.
Oh, illegal possession of a firearm too?
아, 총기 불법 소지도요?
This story pulls out all the stops.
이 이야기는 모든 것을 해결합니다.
Completely.
완전히.
What you up to?
요즘 뭐해요?
Are you now playing spy under the eyes of the police?
당신은 지금 경찰의 눈앞에서 스파이 역할을 하고 있습니까?
This is a massive deal,
이건 엄청난 거래야,
so we were very careful.
그래서 우리는 매우 조심했어요.
That's 30kg of meth.
그것은 30kg의 메스입니다.
Hey.
여기요.
What is this supposed to be about?
이게 무슨 내용일까요?
I have a friend in the Jaegeon group.
재건그룹에 친구가 있어요 .
I asked him what kind of person you are.
나는 그에게 당신이 어떤 사람인지 물었습니다.
And?
그리고?
I was told it was safe to contact you.
연락해도 안전하다고 들었습니다 .
And I did.
그리고 나는 그랬다.
And?
그리고?
What do you want to tell me?
나에게 무엇을 말하고 싶나요?
Take care of Jung Gicheul for us.
우리를 위해 정기철을 돌봐주세요 .
How?
어떻게?
Let him rot in prison for the rest of his life.
평생 감옥에서 썩게 해주세요 .
Hey, come here.
이봐요, 이리와요.
Closer, you bastards.
더 가까이, 이 개자식들아.
We can provide you with the evidence.
우리는 당신에게 증거를 제공할 수 있습니다.
They imprison a criminal to help this chaotic world.
그들은 이 혼란스러운 세상을 돕기 위해 범죄자를 투옥합니다 .
From now on you will be provided with ample compensation.
이제부터 충분한 보상을 받으실 수 있습니다.
Just one.
딱 하나만.
How? Something else?
어떻게? 다른 것?
The Jaegeon group is a shambles,
재건그룹은 엉망이고,
cover us for it.
우리를 덮으십시오.
Mann.
만.
This is crazy.
이건 미친 짓이야.
Sir.
선생님.
I want to lay out a larger plan.
좀 더 큰 계획을 세우고 싶습니다 .
I do not believe it.
난 그거 안 믿어.
How large?
얼마나 커?
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
We should give you at least a house the size of Gangnam Police.
강남경찰서만한 집이라도 드려야죠 .
That's life.
인생이 다 그렇지.
In the end you are alone.
결국 당신은 혼자입니다.
This is Yu Euijeong.
유의정 입니다.
I'm just following Hwang Mingoo's car.
황민구 차를 따라가는 중이에요.
OPERATING ROOM
수술실
Captain Seok will pull through.
석 선장이 돌파할 것이다.
Do not worry.
걱정 하지마.
Inspector Yu just called me.
방금 유 경위가 전화했어요.
Hwang Mingoo has arrested Jung Gicheul and is taking him to the station.
황민구는 정기철을 체포 해 경찰서로 데려가고 있다.
Hwang Mingoo? Why he?
황민구? 왜 그 사람?
Apparently the members of the Gangnam Union have revolted.
강남조합원 들이 반란을 일으킨 것 같습니다 .
Why the hell are you telling me...
도대체 왜 나한테 말하는거야...
Why are you telling me this now?
왜 지금 나에게 이런 말을 하는 걸까요?
You know his arrest is the end of our investigation, right?
그 사람 체포 로 수사가 끝나는 거 아시죠 ?
-Hey, Detective Ko. -Ja, Sir?
-안녕하세요, 고형사님. - 예, 선생님?
How much do you get for that?
그걸로 얼마를 받나요?
10 million won?
1000만원?
You can't earn that much in life.
인생에서 그렇게 많은 돈을 벌 수는 없습니다 .
10 million. My dear.
10000000. 자기.
Right, Mr. Jung?
그렇죠, 정 선생님?
I said I would lock you up.
나는 당신을 가두겠다고 말했습니다 .
At least it's not for adultery,
적어도 간통죄는 아니죠
so not quite as embarrassing.
그래서 별로 당황스럽지 않아요.
That's why you should have listened to me.
그렇기 때문에 당신은 내 말을 들었어야 했어요.
How did it go?
어떻게 됐나요?
How is Dohyung?
도현이는 어때요?
He's recovering, don't worry too much.
회복 중이니 너무 걱정하지 마세요.
How is Jung Gicheul?
정기철씨는 어떤가요?
I was able to free him.
나는 그를 풀어줄 수 있었습니다.
I think he's ok.
내 생각엔 그 사람 괜찮은 것 같아.
We found traces of meth in Hwang Mingoo's car.
황민구의 차에서 필로폰 흔적이 발견됐습니다 .
Apparently Choi Jungbae and Hwang Mingoo have made a pact.
최정배 와 황민구가 약속을 한 것으로 알려졌다.
How do you feel?
기분이 어때요?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Choi Jungbae and Hwang Mingoo. The bastards got together.
최정배와 황민구. 놈들이 모였습니다.
All our boys
우리 소년들 모두
turned against me.
나에게 등을 돌렸다.
But does Choi Jungbae know
그런데 최정배는 알고 있을까?
who is our business partner in Japan?
일본에서 우리의 사업 파트너는 누구입니까?
Only I know that.
그건 나만 알고 있어요.
We have to get our material back first .
우리 는 먼저 자료 를 되찾아야 합니다 .
How? The police support him.
어떻게? 경찰은 그를 지원합니다.
Do you have any idea?
어떤 생각이 있나요?
Our main focus now is,
지금 우리의 주요 초점은,
to put pressure on the Gangnam Union.
강남노조를 압박하려고요.
Let's make sure Captain Seok's death wasn't in vain.
석 선장의 죽음이 헛되지 않았는지 확인하자 .
To catch these guys
이놈들을 잡으려면
will that create enough pressure?
그러면 충분한 압력이 생길까요?
We don't want to eliminate the Gangnam Union .
우리는 강남노조를 없애고 싶지 않습니다 .
We want to narrow down your potential partners to just one.
우리는 귀하의 잠재적 파트너를 단 한 명으로 좁히고 싶습니다 .
Air Meth Jordan. It's been a while.
에어 메스 조던. 오랜만이야.
mr. Lee Hokwang.
씨. 이호광.
You are under arrest for violating the BTM Act.
귀하를 BTM법 위반 혐의로 체포합니다 .
Damned!
저주 받은!
You bastard!
이 개자식!
-Damned. -Come with me.
-저주 받은. -날 따라와.
Hello Sir!
안녕하세요 선생님!
-What's up? -Jungbae.
-무슨 일이야? -정배.
We're finished.
끝났습니다.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Those who should buy our material
우리 자료를 사야하는 사람들
suddenly everyone disappeared.
갑자기 모두가 사라졌습니다.
What the hell are you saying?
대체 무슨 말을 하는 거야?
All our customers are dried out.
우리 고객님들 모두 말랐어요.
Damned ...
저주받은 ...
All dealers relevant to Choi Jungbae have been taken out of circulation.
최정배 관련 딜러는 모두 유통이 중단되었습니다.
Now they should go with their remaining partner
이제 남은 파트너와 함께 가야 합니다.
successfully conclude a deal.
성공적으로 거래를 성사시켰습니다.
Japan and China are ready for their arrest.
일본과 중국은 체포 준비를 마쳤다.
Everything is in your hands now, Detective Park.
이제 모든 것이 당신 손에 달려있습니다, 박 형사님.
Besides that, ...
그 외에도 ...
...how is Dohyung now?
...도형이는 지금 어때요?
He is in a normal ward.
그는 일반 병동에 있습니다.
He is recovering.
그는 회복 중입니다.
Where do you want to go?
어디로 가고 싶나요?
Get our stuff.
우리 물건을 가져오세요.
You shouldn't do that.
그렇게 해서는 안 됩니다.
They're looking for you. It is dangerous.
그들은 당신을 찾고 있습니다. 위험 해요.
You and me,
너와 나,
we risked everything.
우리는 모든 위험을 감수했습니다.
We can't waste our time here.
여기서 시간을 낭비할 수는 없습니다 .
Boss.
사장.
It is as you say.
당신이 말한 대로입니다.
I risked everything too.
나도 모든 것을 위험에 빠뜨렸다.
Boss.
사장.
Remember how you said
당신이 어떻게 말했는지 기억하세요
Should I stop if it gets too hard?
너무 힘들면 그만둬야 할까요 ?
Why didn't you stop?
왜 멈추지 않았나요?
I wanted a normal life.
나는 평범한 삶을 원했습니다.
Let's be honest.
솔직하게 말해보자.
For shits like us to live a normal life...
우리 같은 놈들이 평범하게 살 수 있게...
Aren't you expecting too much?
너무 많은 걸 기대하는 거 아냐?
"Could I turn back time,
"시간을 되돌릴 수 있을까?
"I would have the most normal life in the world."
"나는 세상에서 가장 평범한 삶을 살 것이다."
Have you never had that thought?
그런 생각은 해본 적 없나요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
Become normal...
평범해지다...
I went too far for that.
그러기엔 내가 너무 멀리 갔다.
That's all? What about his lackey?
그게 다야? 그의 부족한 사람은 어떻습니까?
I said I wanted a manhunt for all three, including the blind man.
나는 맹인을 포함해 세 사람 모두를 수색하고 싶다고 말했습니다 .
I found out,
내가 발견,
that bastard Seo Jongryeol
그 새끼 서종렬
is being questioned in protective custody at the SMPA .
SMPA에서 보호구금 심문을 받고 있다.
Suddenly he's in protective custody?
갑자기 보호 구금 상태가 되었나요?
Damn, the bastard can't even get arrested right now.
젠장, 그 새끼는 지금 당장 체포도 못 하잖아.
What about the other lackey, Kwon Seungho?
또 다른 하수인 권승호 는 어떤가 ?
I wanted to put the bastard on the wanted list,
그 놈을 수배 목록에 넣고 싶었는데 ,
but it didn't work.
하지만 작동하지 않았습니다.
Damned. Why not?
저주 받은. 왜 안 돼?
I entered his name on the police intranet, but to no avail.
경찰 인트라넷에 그의 이름을 입력했지만 아무 소용이 없었습니다.
Maybe it was deleted.
어쩌면 삭제되었을 수도 있습니다.
That does not make sense.
그건 말이 안 돼요.
He's not exactly dead. Why doesn't this work?
그는 정확히 죽은 것이 아닙니다. 왜 이것이 작동하지 않습니까?
Moment.
순간.
Stop the manhunt.
수색을 중단하세요.
Stop the search?
검색을 중지하시겠습니까?
Who are you?
누구세요?
What's the point of staring?
쳐다보는 게 무슨 소용이 있나요?
Hey, wait a minute.
잠깐만요.
You're probably the Chinese boss.
당신은 아마도 중국인 상사일 겁니다.
You have accepted our material,
귀하는 우리의 자료를 수락했습니다.
so you have to pay him.
그래서 당신은 그에게 돈을 지불해야합니다.
Ask Jung Gicheul about the money.
정기철에게 돈에 대해 물어보세요.
You made the deal with him, not me.
당신은 내가 아니라 그 사람과 거래를 했습니다 .
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
According to your logic
당신의 논리에 따르면
So can I get our product back like this?
그럼 우리 제품을 이대로 돌려받을 수 있을까요?
like you got it from him.
마치 당신이 그에게서 얻은 것처럼요.
You motherfucker, do you want to die?
이 새끼야, 죽고 싶냐?
Stop. That's just how he expresses himself.
멈추다. 그가 자신을 표현하는 방법은 바로 이것이다.
Stop.
멈추다.
It's ok.
괜찮아요.
Let me meet with Lee Haeryun.
이해련씨를 만나보겠습니다.
I have something to say to her.
나는 그녀에게 할 말이 있습니다.
You can tell me.
당신은 나에게 말할 수 있습니다.
Nun ...
수녀님 ...
The fact that the material flows into the market also benefits you, right?
물질이 시장으로 유입된다는 사실 도 당신에게 이익이 되겠죠?
We eliminated Jung Gicheul and the Jargon group.
정기철 과 전문 용어 그룹을 제거했습니다.
And we have a big bull to cover us.
그리고 우리에게는 우리를 덮을 큰 황소가 있습니다 .
So why don't you work with us?
그럼 우리와 함께 일해보는 게 어때요?
We want you to connect us with Japan.
우리는 일본과 우리를 연결해 주길 바랍니다.
Only then can we do business.
그래야만 사업을 할 수 있습니다.
Did you really have to go that far, sir?
정말 그렇게까지 가야만 했나요?
At least he'll be buried in the national cemetery.
적어도 그는 국립묘지에 안장될 것이다.
Nothing good happens without sacrifice.
희생 없이는 좋은 일이 일어나지 않습니다.
Please don't tell Detective Park about this.
이 사실을 박형사에게 말하지 마세요 .
He's having a hard time anyway.
어쨌든 그는 힘든 시간을 보내고 있습니다.
You don't want to make it any harder for him, do you?
당신은 그 사람을 더 힘들게 만들고 싶지 않습니까?
Hey, Euijeong.
안녕, 의정.
Hi, Gicheul.
안녕, 기철아.
Why didn't you ever answer?
왜 한 번도 대답하지 않았나요?
I was worried.
내가 걱정했다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Something came up.
뭔가 떠올랐어요.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
Naturally.
당연히.
Is Seungho with you?
승호도 같이 있어?
Are you both safe?
너희 둘 다 안전하니?
And.
그리고.
When I'm done with this,
이 일이 끝나면,
I'll come back to you. Just wait a little longer.
나는 당신에게 돌아올 것이다. 조금만 더 기다려주세요.
Next time I'll call.
다음에는 제가 전화할게요.
Dieser Bastard Kwon Seungho.
다이저 바스타드 권승호.
What about him?
그 사람은 어때요?
We can't check him.
우리는 그를 확인할 수 없습니다.
How did he even get to you?
그 사람이 어떻게 당신한테 다가왔나요?
Jung Gicheul's girlfriend, the fucking policewoman.
정기철의 여자친구, 빌어먹을 경찰.
It says he has known her since she was little.
그는 그녀를 어렸을 때부터 알고 지냈다고 합니다.
You monkeys! Why are you telling me this now?
원숭이들아! 왜 지금 나에게 이런 말을 하는 걸까요?
At I...
나는 ...
Sir.
선생님.
I think I know how we do
내 생각엔 우리가 어떻게 지내는지 알 것 같아
Kwon Seungho and Jung Gicheul can catch.
권승호 와 정기철이 잡을 수 있다.
Yu Euijeong und Lee Haeryun.
유의정과 이해련.
Your people are supposed to pursue both.
당신의 사람들은 두 가지를 모두 추구해야 합니다.
Jung Gicheul and Kwon Seungho will definitely follow them.
정기철과 권승호는 반드시 그들을 따라갈 것이다.
Why?
왜?
Kwon Seungho and Lee Haeryun.
권승호와 이해련.
Jung Gicheul and Yu Euijeong.
정기철과 유의정.
So they formed as couples.
그래서 그들은 커플로 결성되었습니다.
They are simply dangerous. What they have to get.
그들은 단순히 위험합니다. 그들이 얻어야 할 것.
You guys can be really smart sometimes.
너희들은 때로 정말 똑똑할 수도 있다.
Seriously? Coffee at this time?
진지하게? 이때 커피?
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
Hello. I'm really looking forward to meeting you.
안녕하세요. 나는 정말로 당신을 만나기를 고대하고 있습니다.
We've heard a lot about you.
우리는 당신에 대해 많이 들었습니다.
They are even more beautiful than I expected.
그들은 내가 기대했던 것보다 훨씬 더 아름답습니다.
You are funny.
당신은 재밌어요.
Yes, I'm pretty funny.
네, 저는 꽤 재밌어요.
Where is the material?
자료는 어디에 있나요?
First
첫 번째
we would like to introduce ourselves.
우리는 우리 자신을 소개하고 싶습니다.
Please.
제발.
They are very suspicious.
그들은 매우 의심스럽습니다.
Anyone who has betrayed their boss shouldn't be surprised.
상사를 배신한 사람은 놀라서는 안됩니다.
Deceived?
속았나요?
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 뜻 이니?
The weak are weeded out.
약한 사람들은 제거됩니다.
That's how it is in our business.
그것이 우리 사업의 방식입니다.
The strong like us should join forces.
우리처럼 강한 사람들은 힘을 합쳐야 합니다.
They're planning pretty big.
그들은 꽤 큰 계획을 세우고 있습니다.
We are indeed planning big.
우리는 실제로 큰 계획을 세우고 있습니다.
It was even my suggestion that we take 30kg.
심지어 30kg을 먹으라는 제안도 있었어요 .
We must act quickly and compensate the Japanese.
우리는 신속하게 행동하여 일본인에게 보상해야 합니다.
And the place.
그리고 장소.
You know where, yes?
어디인지 아세요?
And.
그리고.
I roughly know the area
나는 대략 그 지역을 알고 있다
But I drank a lot yesterday, so I'm not sure right now.
그런데 어제는 술을 많이 마셔서 지금은 잘 모르겠어요.
Where else was it?
또 어디에 있었나요?
Go there,
저기로가,
and deliver the material on time.
그리고 제 시간에 자료를 전달합니다.
And send us the money immediately if you have it from Japan.
그리고 일본에서 돈이 있으면 즉시 우리에게 보내주세요.
Oh yes, there.
아, 그렇죠.
Ok.
좋아요.
There will be no setbacks,
차질이 없을 것입니다,
as was the case with Mr. Jung?
정 선생님의 경우도 그랬나요?
There were always problems when the guy was there, right?
그 사람이 거기 있으면 항상 문제가 있었죠 ?
It was me who constantly had to clean up his mess.
그의 엉망진창을 끊임없이 청소해야했던 것은 바로 나였습니다 .
Let's get this done.
이 작업을 완료합시다.
Let's do this.
이렇게 해보자.
Miss.
놓치다.
You don't know her very well.
당신은 그녀를 잘 알지 못합니다.
Why were you
왜 그랬어?
so amicably?
그렇게 우호적으로?
Hallo?
어이?
Seungho, I did it like this.
승호씨, 제가 이렇게 했어요.
The deal is in Pohang tomorrow.
거래는 내일 포항에서 합니다.
Thank you very much, Haeryun.
정말 고마워요, 해련님.
But we don't know what Choi Jungbae is planning,
하지만 최정배가 무슨 계획을 하고 있는지는 알 수 없고 ,
so be careful.
그러니 조심해.
Ok.
좋아요.
They know you are close to her.
그들은 당신이 그녀와 가깝다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Do you think they trust her?
그 사람들이 그녀를 믿을 것 같나요?
With a huge fortune at your fingertips,
당신의 손끝에 막대한 재산이 있고 ,
these fools can no longer see clearly.
이 바보들은 더 이상 명확하게 볼 수 없습니다.
Choi Jungbae is sending the material to the Japanese in Pohang tomorrow.
최정배가 내일 포항에서 일본인에게 자료를 보낼 예정이다.
Jung Gicheul plant,
정기철공장,
To take the money he receives from Choi Jungbae.
최정배에게서 받은 돈을 빼앗기 위해 .
When the ship leaves tomorrow,
내일 배가 떠날 때,
Oyama will receive it in two days.
오야마가 이틀 안에 받을 거예요.
That will happen.
그런 일이 일어날 것입니다.
I'm putting China and Japan on standby.
중국과 일본을 대기 시키겠습니다 .
This time it has to work.
이번에는 작동해야 합니다.
Alongside, ...
나란히, ...
...how can I contact Dohyung?
...도형이한테 어떻게 연락하나요?
Is he really okay?
그 사람 정말 괜찮아요?
No worries.
걱정 마.
His injury requires further rest.
그의 부상은 더 많은 휴식이 필요합니다.
We'll soon be there.
우리는 곧 거기에 도착할 것입니다.
Let's focus on the deal.
거래에 집중해보자.
ATTORNEY CHO CHANGSIK
창식 변호사 창식 변호사
TO THE LATE SEOK DOHYUNG
故 석도형 님께
I'm from the Gangnam Police Department and I have a few questions.
저는 강남경찰서 출신 인데 몇 가지 질문이 있습니다.
Also ...
또한 ...
Are you the wife of the deceased?
당신은 고인의 아내입니까?
And.
그리고.
What was the name of the deceased?
고인의 이름은 무엇이었나요?
Seok Dohyung.
석도형.
What is it about?
무엇에 관한 것입니까?
Do you know Detective Park Junmo?
박준모 형사를 아시나요?
Tomorrow they'll try again
내일 그들은 다시 시도할 것이다
to meet the Japanese in Pohang.
포항에서 일본인을 만나러.
Go to Pohang.
포항으로 가세요.
Should the deal
거래를 해야 할까요?
fail again this time,
이번에도 실패하고,
Your father wo n't just watch it.
네 아버지는 그걸 보고만 계시지 않을 거야.
No worries.
걱정 마.
He calls himself my father even though he uses me,
나를 이용하면서도 자기를 아버지라 부르며
but I trust Kwon Seungho more.
하지만 나는 권승호를 더 믿는다.
Hey, what's up?
무슨 일이야?
Here?
여기?
I'm on the 12th floor.
저는 12층에 있어요.
Are you here?
여기 계세요?
Sir.
선생님.
Why did you come all this way?
왜 이렇게까지 왔나요 ?
It's like you said. We won the jackpot.
당신이 말한 것과 같습니다. 우리는 대박을 얻었습니다.
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 뜻 이니?
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Can we talk?
우리 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까요?
I know you're in there.
당신이 거기 있다는 걸 알아요.
Let's talk about Kwon Seungho.
권승호에 대해 이야기해보자.
It does not take long.
오래 걸리지 않습니다.
We're busy people, I'll get straight to the point.
우리는 바쁜 사람들이기 때문에 곧바로 요점을 말씀드리겠습니다.
Where are Jung Gicheul and Kwon Seungho now?
정기철 과 권승호는 지금 어디에 있나요?
I would like to know that.
나는 그것을 알고 싶습니다.
You know this woman, yes?
이 여자 아시죠?
Mr. Jung's girlfriend.
정씨의 여자친구.
More like a lover.
연인에 가깝습니다.
She is actually married.
그녀는 실제로 결혼했습니다.
With a Park Junmo.
박준모와 함께.
What a disaster her life is.
그녀의 인생은 참으로 재앙입니다.
She is married?
그녀는 결혼했어요?
He's a police officer too?
그 사람도 경찰이에요?
But you know,
하지만 아시다시피,
what's even more amazing?
더 놀라운 것은 무엇입니까?
This man is not that man.
이 사람은 저 사람이 아닙니다.
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Park Junmo is not Park Junmo.
박준모는 박준모가 아니다.
Here.
여기.
Ta-da!
짜잔!
The Kwon Seungho you know.
당신이 아는 권승호.
Kwon Seungho. The bastard is Park Junmo.
권승호. 그 놈은 박준모.
Police Chief Park Junmo of the Eumseong Police Department.
음성 경찰서 박준모 경찰서장 .
You were played something.
당신은 뭔가를 연주했습니다.
Just tell me where Kwon Seungho is.
권승호가 어디 있는지 알려주세요 .
I'll put him in handcuffs immediately.
즉시 수갑을 채우겠습니다.
So tell me.
그러니 나에게 말해봐.
We are on the same page.
우리는 같은 페이지에 있습니다.
Even if he is a police officer,
아무리 경찰이라도,
what he did as an undercover cop is enough
그가 잠복경찰로서 한 일은 그것으로 충분하다
that he will spend life in prison.
감옥에서 평생을 보낼 것이라고 합니다.
Haeryun.
해륜.
Do you want to wait in China?
중국에서 기다리시겠습니까?
Die Situation
다이 상황
in Korea is quite unsafe.
한국은 정말 위험해요.
When searching for the substance, who knows what will happen.
물질을 검색할 때 무슨 일이 일어날지 누가 알겠습니까?
If the deal fails again this time,
이번에도 거래가 실패하면
Your father won't just watch.
너희 아버지는 보고만 계시지 않을 것이다.
Hallo?
어이?
It's me, Haeryun.
나야, 해륜.
Hello, Haeryun.
안녕하세요, 해륜님.
I was just going to call you.
방금 전화하려고 했어요.
We're leaving now.
우리는 지금 떠날 예정이다.
Don't worry too much.
너무 걱정하지 마세요.
Everything will be fine.
다 괜찮을거야.
Can I ask you something?
뭐 좀 물어봐도 될까요?
You've been very nice to me all this time.
당신은 그동안 나에게 아주 친절했어요.
Did you mean that honestly?
솔직히 그런 뜻이었나요?
Was?
였다?
This is such a...
이것은 그런 ...
Answer me. Did you mean that honestly?
대답 해. 솔직히 그런 뜻이었나요?
And? Have you considered it?
그리고? 고려해 보셨나요?
If I tell you where Kwon Seungho is,
권승호가 어디 있는지 말하면
will you keep your word?
약속을 지킬 것인가?
Come! Of course I will.
오다! 물론이죠.
Can you see it,
보이시나요,
Kwon Seungho - The Best Of Park Junmo,
권승호 - 박준모의 베스트,
I'll have him in the bag before he even notices.
그가 눈치 채기도 전에 나는 그를 가방에 넣을 것입니다 .
No worries.
걱정 마.
You know what?
그거 알아?
I'm getting tired of this business too.
나도 이 일에 질려가고 있어.
My father called.
아버지가 전화했어요.
I should come back.
나는 다시 와야 한다.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Should I go to Changchun?
창춘에 갈까?
Or stay in Korea?
아니면 한국에 머물까요?
Listen,
듣다,
Haeryun.
해륜.
Neither in Korea nor in China.
한국에도 없고 중국에도 없습니다.
Until it's all over,
다 끝날 때까지,
you should stay in Hong Kong.
너는 홍콩에 있어야 해.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Why did you do that?
왜 그런 짓을 한거야?
Because I have someone
나에겐 누군가가 있으니까
I want to protect in my heart.
마음속으로 지키고 싶습니다.
This is our last chance.
이번이 마지막 기회입니다.
Will everything work out?
모든 것이 잘 될까요?
Everything will work.
모든 것이 작동합니다.
Boss.
사장.
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
I drive.
내가 운전.
There's a police officer out there.
밖에 경찰이 있어요.
Have you forgotten that there are always two of them?
항상 두 개가 있다는 것을 잊으셨습니까 ?
I'll do it.
나는 그것을 할 거 야.
You should go.
당신은 가야합니다.
I lure him away.
나는 그를 유인합니다.
Run before reinforcements arrive.
지원군이 도착하기 전에 달려가세요.
Lee Haeryun, pull yourself together.
이해련 씨, 힘내세요.
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
Don't go to China.
중국에 가지 마세요.
If they find out you blew it,
당신이 망친 걸 그들이 알게 된다면 ,
you are no longer sure.
당신은 더 이상 확신할 수 없습니다.
Why?
왜?
So are we.
우리도 마찬가지입니다.
You have to survive, no matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도 살아남아야 합니다.
And then
그런 다음
go to the man,
그 사람에게 가서
that you trust.
당신이 신뢰하는 것.
You bastard.
이 개자식.
Damn bastard.
빌어먹을 놈.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Hallo.
어이.
Here is the material.
여기에 자료가 있습니다.
Fuck.
못쓰게 만들다.
The product has been handed over.
상품이 인도되었습니다.
Boat name is Blue Dragon.
보트 이름은 블루 드래곤(Blue Dragon)입니다.
Repeat: Blue Dragon.
반복: 블루 드래곤.
This is Korea. The freighter Blue Dragon has left Pohang.
여기는 한국입니다. 화물선 블루드래곤호가 포항을 떠났습니다.
Yes, the captain is the courier.
네, 선장이 택배기사입니다.
Ok.
좋아요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Boss.
사장.
Was?
였다?
I think you should stay here.
내 생각엔 당신이 여기 있어야 할 것 같아요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I'll take care of myself
나는 내 자신을 돌볼 것이다
about the guys.
남자들에 대해.
You can't do this alone, you crazy.
너 혼자서는 이걸 할 수 없어, 미친놈아.
I know.
알아요.
Young Gicheul.
영기철.
Let's stop here.
여기서 멈추자.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Kwon Seungho.
권승호.
It's all over, you bastard.
다 끝났어, 이 개자식아.
What the hell are you doing?
당신은 뭐 해요?
Listen, Jung Gicheul.
들어봐 정기철.
You wanted a normal life,
당신은 평범한 삶을 원했고,
but you didn't have a chance?
그런데 기회가 없었나요?
No.
아니요.
That is not true.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다.
That's just an excuse.
그것은 단지 변명일 뿐입니다.
I hope,
나는 희망,
that in the end you will pay for everything,
결국 당신은 모든 비용을 지불하게 될 것입니다.
what you have done.
당신이 한 일.
Kwon Seungho.
권승호.
Let's end it here.
여기서 끝내자.
Hey, Choi Jungbae.
안녕하세요 최정배님.
Why are you alone? Where is Jung Gicheul?
왜 혼자예요? 정기철은 어디에 있나요?
You're not even bringing people with you anymore?
이제 더 이상 사람들을 데려오지 않으시나요?
Let's end this all here, okay?
여기서 모두 끝내자, 알았지?
Everything is over.
모든 게 끝났어.
He's really alone here.
그는 여기 정말 혼자예요.
What the hell is this damn monkey saying ?
도대체 이 망할 원숭이가 무슨 말을 하는 거지 ?
Is this a bluff?
이게 허세인가요?
You motherfucker. Come here.
이 개자식아. 이리 오세요.
Damned.
저주 받은.
What do you want to do alone?
혼자 무엇을 하고 싶나요?
I mean, shit,
내 말은, 젠장,
Do you want to fight against the three of us all alone?
우리 셋이서 단 둘이서 싸우고 싶나요 ?
What the hell ...?
대체 무슨 일이야...?
Let's disappear.
사라지자.
Let's get out of there!
거기서 나가자!
You were a cop?
당신은 경찰이었나요?
You fucking motherfucker. You had to be a cop!
이 빌어먹을 개자식아. 당신은 경찰이 되어야 했어요!
Damned!
저주 받은!
Drop the knife!
칼을 버려라!
Drop!
떨어지다!
Arrest her.
그녀를 체포하세요.
On the ground!
지상에!
Crap.
쓰레기.
Put on the ground!
땅바닥에 눕혀라!
Okay, you asshole!
알았어, 이 멍청아!
Kwon Seungho, you bastard!
권승호, 이 새끼야!
Asshole!
항문!
Fuck!
못쓰게 만들다!
Kwon Seungho, du Hurensohn!
권승호, 뒤렌손!
Ok, enough now.
이제 충분합니다.
Kwon Seungho, du Mistkerl!
권승호, du Mistkerl!
Ok!
좋아요!
Anyone who doesn't want to listen gets slapped.
듣기 싫은 사람은 뺨을 맞는다.
Invite them.
그들을 초대하세요.
Out of the way, please!
비켜주세요!
YOKOHAMA, JAPAN
YOKOHAMA, JAPAN
We have news from Korea. The operation can begin.
한국 소식이 있습니다. 수술이 시작될 수 있습니다.
Captain, Donghobang's boss Lee Oson is inside.
선장, 동호방의 상사 이오손이 그 안에 있다.
They could offer fierce resistance.
그들은 맹렬한 저항을 할 수도 있습니다.
When the law fears the underworld,
법이 지하세계를 두려워할 때,
become our children
우리의 자녀가 되어주세요
have to live in barbaric times.
야만적인 시대에 살아야 한다.
We quickly relocate their hiding place.
우리는 그들의 은신처를 신속하게 이전합니다.
Remember, this operation is intended to completely destroy Donghobang.
기억하세요, 이 작전은 동호방을 완전히 파괴하기 위한 것입니다.
Drop your weapons and surrender!
무기를 버리고 항복하라!
Anyone who resists
저항하는 사람은 누구나
will be killed!
죽을 것이다!
Father, please save me.
아버지, 저를 구해주세요.
Yoon Wongil?
윤원길?
Good job.
잘했어요.
Thanks sir.
고마워요 선생님.
Now you have something to say to the gang.
이제 갱단에게 할 말이 있습니다.
Oyama!
오야마!
You should be a drug dealer, not a murderer.
살인자가 아니라 마약상이 되어야 합니다 .
Call your family. say,
가족에게 전화하세요. 말하다,
They'll never come home again.
그들은 다시는 집에 돌아오지 않을 것입니다.
The authorities in Korea, Japan and China
한국, 일본, 중국 당국
have been successful together
함께 성공했어요
an international drug investigation was carried out.
국제 마약 조사 가 수행되었습니다.
The bosses of the Seoul- based Gangnam Union,
서울 강남노조 간부님들 ,
Choi Jungbae and Hong Heesung,
최정배, 홍희성,
sent meth maker Yoon Wongil,
메스 제조사 윤원길을 보냈고,
also known as Professor Yoon, to Changchun in Jilin, China.
윤 교수로도 중국 길림성 창춘에 파견.
With the support of the local gang Donghobang
지역 갱단 동호방의 지원으로
They set up a drug factory.
그들은 마약 공장을 세웠습니다.
They turned to Yoshioka-gumi, a Yakuza gang
They turned to Yoshioka-gumi, a Yakuza gang
in Yokohama, Japan, and their underboss,
일본 요코하마에 있는 그들의 상사와
den Korea-Japaner namens Oyama Tsuyoshi,
den Korea-Japaner namens Oyama Tsuyoshi,
Korean name Oh Chunseok.
한국 이름은 오춘석.
They agreed to a meth deal at 10 million yen per kilogram,
그들은 1킬로그램당 1,000만엔에 필로폰 거래를 하기로 합의했고 ,
equivalent to 80 million Korean won...
한화로 8000만원 정도 ...
PLAN FOR INTERNATIONAL FREE CITY FAILS FOLLOWING FINANCING
국제자유도시 계획은 자금조달로 인해 실패
STOP AT THE RAILWAY CROSSING!
건널목에 멈춰주세요!
SEOK DOHYUNG
석도형
Dohyung
도형
would be very proud of you.
당신이 매우 자랑스러울 것입니다.
So much has happened
너무 많은 일이 일어났어요
during the investigation.
조사 중에.
Do you think we can?
우리가 할 수 있을 것 같아?
be who we were again?
우리는 다시 누구였을까?
Euijeong.
의정.
You two look good together.
둘이 사이가 좋아 보이는군요.
Put the gun down.
총을 내려놓으세요.
Drop them.
버리세요.
Gicheul.
기철.
Don't make any more wrong decisions.
더 이상 잘못된 결정을 내리지 마세요 .
Wrong decisions?
잘못된 결정인가요?
To protect you two,
두 분을 보호하기 위해,
I gave up on everyone who stuck by me.
나는 나를 붙잡은 모든 사람을 포기했습니다 .
That was a wrong decision.
그것은 잘못된 결정이었습니다.
Young Gicheul.
영기철.
That is not true.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다.
All your decisions were simply wrong.
당신의 모든 결정은 단순히 잘못되었습니다.
So drop them.
그러니 버리세요.
Drop the weapon immediately!
즉시 무기를 버려라!
Answer me a question.
질문에 답해주세요.
Why was I spared?
나는 왜 구원받았는가?
Why?
왜?
And you, Euijeong?
그리고 의정씨는요?
Have you ever been honest with me?
나한테 솔직하게 말한 적 있어?
Do you just have me?
나밖에 없나요?
used for the investigation?
수사에 이용됐나?
Whether I was honest or not,
내가 솔직했든 아니든,
doesn't change anything.
아무것도 바꾸지 않습니다.
Gicheul.
기철.
I believed the best thing would be
가장 좋은 게 있을 거라 믿었어
to stop you from further crimes.
더 이상의 범죄를 막기 위해.
I may be a wicked man,
나는 사악한 사람일지도 모른다.
but you have betrayed my trust and deceived me.
그러나 당신은 나의 믿음을 배반 하고 나를 속였습니다.
Isn't that a crime?
그거 범죄 아닌가요?
That's it.
그게 다야.
And we will certainly have to pay for it.
그리고 우리는 반드시 그에 대한 대가를 지불해야 할 것입니다.
If not in lifetime,
평생 안되면
then after death.
그럼 죽은 뒤에.
You will pay in your lifetime.
당신은 평생 동안 지불하게 될 것입니다 .
The rest of your life
남은 인생
you won't be happy anymore.
당신은 더 이상 행복하지 않을 것입니다.
Gicheul!
기철!
Gicheul.
기철.
No.
아니요.
Wake up, Gicheul.
일어나, 기철아.
Gicheul. Young Gicheul.
기철. 영기철.
Gicheul.
기철.
-Hello, this is Park Junmo. -Please, Gicheul.
-안녕하세요. 박준모입니다. -부탁해요, 기철님.
It has just been
방금 그랬어
Young Gicheul
영기철
caught.
잡았다.
Gicheul.
기철.
Gicheul, no.
기철아, 아니야.
Young Gicheul!
영기철님!
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR PROMOTION
승진을 축하합니다
SERVICE AWARD SEOK DOHYUNG
봉사상 석도형
YU EUIJEONG
유의정
SERVICE AWARD PARK JUNMO
봉사상 박준모
Good job.
잘했어요.
YOUNG GICHEUL
어린기철
Subtitles by: Ingo Krallmann
자막: Ingo Krallmann